威尔 · 森特斯: 好了，各位,
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: All right, people,
我们会继续研究这是怎么可能的。
we are gonna keep going to see
how this is even possible.
我们开始暗示实际上老实说从 Dan 的问题来看,
We started hinting at it, I think
actually, honestly, from Dan's question,
这怎么可能？
how is it even possible?
在 JavaScript 中，函数就是所谓的第一类对象。
Well, in JavaScript, functions
are what's called first class objects.
也就是说，它们具有物体的所有特征。
That is to say that they have
all the features of objects.
第一类只是意味着它们拥有对象拥有的一切,
First class just means,
they have everything that objects have,
他们也是。
they have too.
它们是物体的全部特征，这意味着它们可以像物体一样被对待。
They're full features of objects, meaning
they can be treated just like objects.
我们知道不存在通过的问题。
We know that there's
no problem of passing.
假设我声明了一个对象，我不知道，像这样。
Suppose I declared an object,
I don't know, like this.
如果我声明一个对象，它就在那里。
If I declared an object, there it is.
我会毫不犹豫地将其作为输入。
I'd have no problem
passing that as an input.
顺便说一下，在后面的场景中，数组，我们稍后会看到它们只是对象。
Behind the scenes by the way, arrays,
we're gonna see later on are just objects.
顺便说一下，在幕后，函数只是对象。
By the way, behind the scenes,
functions are just objects.
在 JavaScript 的幕后意味着他们可以做所有的事情
Behind the scenes in JavaScript
meaning they can do all the things
物体可以做的事情。
that objects can do.
我们可以把它们赋给变量。
We can assign them to variables.
我们马上就会看到一种特殊的拯救方式
We're gonna see in a moment that's
gonna create a particular way of saving
越来越流行的函数。
functions that is more and more popular.
它们可以被存储为其他物体的属性,
They can be stored as properties of
other objects where they're known as,
作为其他对象的其他属性存储的函数叫什么？
what do we call function stored as
other properties of other objects?
方法，完全正确。
Methods, exactly.
它们可以作为输入，作为参数，传递到其他函数中,
They can be passed as inputs,
as arguments, into other functions,
顺便说一下，根据他们出生的地方，正是丹长大的地方。
by the way, by reference back to where
they were born, exactly as Dan raised.
今天下午我们将看到对我来说最优雅最成熟的,
And we're gonna see this afternoon,
to me the most elegant, sophisticated,
的漂亮特性。
beautiful feature of JavaScript.
可以声明它们，并在运行另一个函数时保存它们。
That they can be declared, saved inside
of the running of another function.
不在那里使用，而是返回出去。
Not used there, but instead returned out.
这给了我们什么样的 JavaScript 特性？
And that gives us what
feature of JavaScript?
讲者二: 闭幕 威尔 · 森塔斯: 结束,
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Closure.
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: Closure,
没错，结束。
exactly, closure.
好了，哪个是我们的高阶函数
All right, so, which of these
is our higher order function and
哪个是我们的复试？
which of these is our callback?
不幸的是，这些幻灯片有答案，不要去读它们。
These slides unfortunately have
the answer, don't read them.
让我们看看亚当，因为他，亚当是我们早期的专家。
But let's turn to Adam because he,
Adam was our earlier expert.
它是复制数组和操作，还是乘法 by2。
Is it copy array and
manipulate or is it multiplyBy2.
亚当，哪个是我们的高阶函数？
Adam, which is our higher order function?
说话人2: 复制数组和操作。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: The copy array and
manipulate.
那么哪个是我们的回调函数呢，布雷登？
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: And
which is our callback function, Brayden?
讲者2: multilyby2。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: MultiplyBy2.
威尔 · 森塔斯: multilyby2。
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: MultiplyBy2.
是的，外部功能可以增加一点婴儿功能,
Yeah, the outer function that
takes in a little baby function,
这是我们的高阶函数。
that's our higher order function.
我们插入的函数是回调函数。
The function we insert in
is our callback function.
就是这样，各位。
And that's it, people.
我仍然记得当我第一次遇到这些深刻的思考。
I still remember when I first
encountered these thinking so profound.
但这是我们的高阶函数。
But this is our high order function.
任何接受或以这种方式返回一个函数的函数。
Any function that takes in, or
by the way returns out a function.
只是用一个术语来描述每个函数。
Just a term describe each function.
我们不需要，你可以想象一种语言，我们需要把它声明为
We don't need to, you can imagine
a language where we need to declare it as
是一个高阶函数。
being a higher order function.
所以它已经准备好接收其他功能了。
So it's ready to receive other functions.
不是在 JavaScript 中，没有问题。
Not in JavaScript, no problem.
在 JavaScript 中，任何接受函数或函数的函数
In JavaScript,
any function that takes in a function or
自动返回一个输出是一个高阶函数。
returns one out automatically
is a higher order function.
他们之间没有什么本质上的不同。
There's nothing inherently
different about them.
高阶函数和回调函数,
Okay, so high order functions and
callbacks,
他们让我们的代码更加干燥。
they keep our code far more dry.
不要重复自己的话。
Don't repeat yourself.
我们写过一次。
We wrote one time.
看看这个，有一次，复制数组操作，然后运行它，就是这样
Look at this, one time, copy array
manipulate, and then when ran it, that's
当我们决定如何处理这些代码的时候。
when we determined what specifically
we would do with some of the code.
这个想法很特别，我们可以在保存一个函数之后再编辑它,
That's really special, the idea that we
can edit a function after we've saved it,
因为我们留了一点空白。
because we left a little bit of it blank.
而不仅仅是编辑我们要用的数据,
And not just edit it with what
data we're gonna have in there,
而是字面上编辑它的代码。
but literally edit its code.
这使得我们的代码更加可重用。
That makes our code saved
profoundly more reusable.
我们可以在很多不同的情况下使用它。
We can use it in so
many different situations.
我们可以除以2，我们可以加上3，任何我们想要的。
We could pass in divide by 2,
we could pass in add 3, anything we want.
这确保了我们也可以编写更具声明性、更具可读性的代码。
This ensures that we can write more
declarative, more readable code as well.
看看下面这个函数，copyArrayManipulate。
Have a look at what this function
down here, copyArrayManipulate.
他们打电话不是为了这个而是为了什么,
They tend to call is not that,
but what, everybody,
他们通常怎么称呼这个函数？
what do they call this function usually?
讲者二: 地图 威尔 · 森塔斯: 地图,
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Map.
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: Map,
确切地说，他们称之为地图，这意味着通过一些数据
exactly they call it map,
it means take some data through some
映射功能，某种改变数据的方法。
mapping functionality,
some way of changing that data.
使用每个元素的更改创建新的数据集合
Create new collection of data with
each of those elements change
根据某个函数，在这种情况下，每个函数乘以2。
according some function, in this case,
multiply each of them by 2.
这是一行非常易读的代码。
That is a very readable line of code.
在现实中，我们需要了解它是如何建立在引擎盖下的，但是
In reality, we need to understand
how it's built under the hood, but
我们不写那个，我们只是大部分时间在用它。
we ain't writing that,
we're just using it most of the time.
这意味着我要写在这里映射这个数据通过这个转换函数,
Meaning I get to write here map this
data by this transformation function,
每个元素乘以2，很容易读懂。
multiply each element by 2,
that's pretty readable.
而如果我这样做。
Versus if I were doing it like that.
看看这个函数的内部，这是我过去必须写的,
Have a look inside that function, that's
what I've had to write in the old days,
用祈使语气。
in the imperative style.
相反，我声明我想过滤或映射这个条件的数据。
Instead I declare I wanna filter or
map this data by this condition.
对不起，在这种情况下，这个数据由这个映射函数来映射。
Sorry, in this case,
this data by this mapping function.
这使得代码非常具有可读性。
That makes for very readable code.
它是函数式编程的核心部分
It's a core part of
functional programming and
更普遍的宣告式编程。
more generally declarative programming.
宣告我想要发生的事情。
Declaring what I wanna have happen.
比如说，我想绘制地图，然后它就发生了，很漂亮。
Say, I wanna map it, and
it happens, beautiful.
这仍然是面试的关键部分,
All right,
it remains a key part of interviewing,
无论是中高级职位面试。
whether for
mid-senior level job interviews.
传入一个函数的概念
And the notion of passing in a function
以一种完全不同的方式运行另一个函数,
to the running of another
function in a very different way,
将成为同步 JavaScript 的主干。
is gonna turn out to be the backbone
of a synchronous JavaScript.
即使我们使用了许诺，即使我们在幕后使用了异步等待,
Even if we're using promises, even if
we're using async await behind the scenes,
将一个函数传递给另一个函数是这些概念的核心。
passing in a function to another function
is gonna be core to those concepts.